(Watch on KonFlix.vip)
[Fate Chooses You]
[Episode 26]
Let's go.
What happened?
It's no use.
They can't be saved.
We all took the Mind-Awakening Pills.
Taking too much of it
damages the heart meridian.
What are you doing?
Lord of Rust-Sword,
your kindness to the Wushuang Society
can only be repaid in the next life.
For the future of the human race,
you must bring the Unparalleled Secret Magic
back to the Central Plains.
You must bring it back to the Central Plains.
Please.
♪ Honor and disgrace; rumors and prejudice ♪
♪ Everyone has their own take ♪
♪ Fingers coated in blood and disasters brought about ♪
Go.
♪ Were never what I wanted ♪
♪ The great way is fading away, besieged by mysterious traps ♪
Lord of Rust-Sword, please go now!
♪ Who dares to treat life and death as nothing? ♪
The immortal sect will catch up if you don't hurry!
♪ In the blink of an eye, the body collapses, and the soul is destroyed ♪
♪ The fire starts raging across the land ♪
♪ What do you think is ♪
♪ The most impressive farewell in the world? ♪
♪ The endless slaughter and massacres ♪
♪ Do not wait until that thin snow on the eaves ♪
♪ Turns a young man's hair white before you regret it ♪
♪ When do you think ♪
♪ The bloody strife will come to an end? ♪
♪ Burn myself to prove it without looking back ♪
♪ Holding the morning glow in hand, I paint the world ♪
♪ The dawn light illuminates the vast sky ♪
There is a path to heaven in the books.
Why bother seeking immortals on Penglai Island?
♪ Honor and disgrace; rumors and prejudice ♪
I will return riding the wind.
♪ Everyone has their own take ♪
Away from this ever-changing world.
♪ Fingers coated in blood and disasters brought about ♪
♪ Were never what I wanted ♪
♪ The great way is fading away, besieged by mysterious traps ♪
♪ Who dares to treat life and death as nothing? ♪
♪ In the blink of an eye, the body collapses, and the soul is destroyed ♪
♪ The fire starts raging across the land ♪
♪ What do you think is ♪
♪ The most impressive farewell in the world? ♪
♪ End these everlasting battles ♪
♪ Holding the morning glow in hand, I paint the world ♪
♪ Someone's got to clean up this mess ♪
Tai Shiqian.
He took the Mind-Awakening Pills.
What is that?
A pill that can instantly
awaken one's mental power.
But if taken too much,
it will backfire,
destroy the heart and meridians,
and lead to certain death.
Lord of Rust-Sword!
Don't come closer.
It's dangerous.
Leave me alone.
Leave.
You've finally come.
Miss Sheng, are you okay?
Oh no.
The people from the Tianyuan Sect have caught up.
Let's go!
Right ahead.
You are so hard to kill.
You bunch of ants.
You should have hidden in the dark ditch
and curled up for the rest of your lives.
But you insisted on coming out
and annoying me.
You lot
should have been crushed
under my foot long ago.
How dare you drag out your feeble existence
to this day?
Today,
if I don't skin you alive
and tear you apart,
how can I vent the hatred in my heart?
At first,
I just wanted to be an ordinary person.
But then I remember that someone like you,
neither human nor demon,
still exists in this world.
You're like a maggot in the gutter,
disgusting to look at.
If you don't die,
how can I be satisfied?
You're but a mere Nascent Soul.
Look at your pathetic state.
You were supposed to be the strongest War Demon,
yet you insisted on being a human.
You gave up your power,
pushed yourself to this state,
and are now at the mercy of others.
How does it feel to lose your power?
You can't even protect yourself.
Lu Qianqiao,
you are nothing but trash.
You are nothing but trash.
You are nothing but trash!
You...
Look at you, so eager to see me.
Did you miss me?
Where is my friend?
Friend?
Are you really that incompetent?
After all this time,
she is still just your friend?
Where exactly is she?
Want to see her?
Follow me.
After all, Xia Xuanzi
is at the Void Stage,
and a long-established Gu master.
Even if you two Nascent Souls
fought to the death,
it'd have been futile.
This young lady was hit by the Bone-Eroding,
Blood-Averting,
and Dream-Crashing
Gu poisons.
Logically, she shouldn't be alive.
But I found
a strange power in her body
protecting her last bit of life.
I used the Giant Spirit Fruit as the main ingredient,
supplemented with Immortal Ginseng Grass,
Red Velvet Lamp,
Green Chiretta,
and Corydalis
to expel the Gu and detoxify her.
Just yesterday,
I've already expelled
the Gu bugs from her body.
Once the residual poison is cleared,
she will wake up soon.
Bone-Eroding and Dream-Crashing poisons are easy to cure.
But Blood-Averting
will attach itself to the blood vessels and meridians.
Using Corydalis
can never remove it completely.
Corydalis
has a strong and fierce
medicinal property.
This young lady is severely injured.
If the wrong medicine is used,
it will backfire.
So,
we should use Wugen fruit instead.
Grind it into powder and dissolve it in water.
The water should be hot but not boiling.
I didn't expect you
to be an expert in pharmacology.
Thank you for saving us.
You are welcome.
Xia Xuanzi
is known as the world's best
Gu master.
To be able to dispel the Gu poison he cast
is also
a pleasure for me.
May I know
who you are?
I'm the master of Qinghong Sect,
Fu Tian.
Have a sip.
You mean, this is the Qinghong Sect?
Yes.
But when I passed by just now,
I saw many craftsmen.
You should be aware that
North Xiang is famous for paper.
Yes.
Our paper mill
has a history of
more than 200 years.
The paper we produce is
thin and even,
white as fine jade,
soft and dense,
insect-proof and heat-resistant.
It's absorbent and dries quickly.
Ink remains vibrant on its surface
and does not fade easily.
It sells very well in the market.
Papermaking?
Isn't this the Qinghong Sect?
Qinghong Sect needs to eat and drink, too.
Without industry
and income,
how can we live?
I know you have some thoughts.
I also know a little about your grudge
against my sect.
But I lack the power
to stop it.
You are the Sect Master,
but you lack the power to act?
Yes.
If one cannot control
the sect members,
then being the Sect Master
is just an empty title.
Any faction in its development
will have some deviations.
A few Dharma Kings
and Branch Masters of our sect
strongly opposed my
benevolent philosophy.
They bewitched the members
and broke free from my control.
Then how do you explain
Bishui Branch's action?
The Bishui Branch's Master and Gui
are both their operatives.
But if it weren't for
the two Protectors and the support
of the Dharma Kings and Vajras this time,
I couldn't have kept this paper mill,
let alone
the financial resources of our sect.
I'm afraid even my title
would have been taken by someone else.
If our sect were united
and working together,
the people of the immortal sect
wouldn't have dared to cross the border and invade us.
They burned down the Sihe Library
that our sect had operated for years.
By the time we rushed over,
it was too late.
The ancient books of a thousand years
were destroyed in a day.
We only had time to save you
and that young lady.
I have a friend
named Lord of Rust-Sword.
Do you know where he is?
The ones buried here
are all from the Wushuang Society.
We don't have their names,
so we didn't set up tombstones for them.
Here lies a young lady
in her twenties.
She looked somewhat pretty.
She used a sword.
So we buried her together with it.
[Xutuo City]
Hurry up.
Hurry up, guys.
Boss.
When will your caravan leave the city?
Tomorrow at noon.
I have 2 friends
who want to travel to the Central Plains.
Bring your own carriage. To get past the pass,
it's 2 taels per person.
Here is the deposit.
Where do we meet tomorrow?
Right here.
Okay.
Hurry.
Come and take a look.
Cantaloupes.
Free if they aren't sweet!
She must have spotted us.
After her!
Tang,
how are your injuries?
I'm fine.
What about the books?
Did you count them?
Are they all here?
Yes, they are.
That's good.
Who is it?
Me.
The people from the immortal sect have caught up.
We must leave immediately.
Your yin energy is stagnant,
and your pulse is rapid.
It seems the Blood-Averting Gu poison hasn't been cleared.
It's still acting up.
I hope I'm not disturbing you.
Song, who delivers the food,
was injured this morning.
I told him to go back and rest.
Since I was on my way,
I brought this food
over to you.
Beef noodles
and Suquan wine.
I don't know
if it suits your taste.
Thank you, Sect Master.
All right.
You're welcome.
You are not a member of my sect.
You don't need to call me Sect Master.
Just call me...
Just call me Fu Tian.
I feel a connection with you
and want to make friends with you.
Can I call you...
Can I call you Lu?
Sure.
Thank you.
Are the noodles not to your taste?
I'm not hungry.
That's a pity.
My chef
cooks very well.
Look at this food box.
Its insulation is excellent.
Let me put it this way,
from the moment the noodles leave the pot to when you eat them,
the temperature won't drop at all.
Look at this lid.
It has a spiral pattern on the rims.
Cover it,
twist it tight,
and it becomes airtight.
Look at this food box again.
It has double walls.
In the gap between the two walls,
if you put in hot water and cover it,
no matter what you put inside,
it will remain hot
for 4 hours.
It really is exquisite.
Such a delicate object.
If it weren't for Goddess Wushuang
designing it,
I'm afraid we would never
have had the fortune to enjoy it in this life.
Goddess Wushuang?
Do you mean that
Qinghong Sect has the Unparalleled Secret Magic?
Yes.
Back then, when I read
the Unparalleled Secret Magic,
I felt some of the things in it
could be used in daily life,
so I recorded them.
I don't know
if I can still find
the original notes now.
Even a single word or sentence would be good.
Sect Master,
could you help me look for it?
Sure.
Lu,
these are just some random notes I took.
They are not complete.
If you need,
I'll send someone to look for more.
Maybe we can still find some
surviving woodblocks.
Thank you, Sect Master.
Lu,
you don't need to be so polite.
In fact, helping you is helping myself.
The Sihe Library
was the lifeblood of our Qinghong Sect.
Many of the books
and collections inside
were already lost to history.
The destruction of the library this time
breaks my heart.
As for those books,
I don't know
how many generations
of time and effort it will take
to fully restore them.
If there is anything
you need my help with,
just ask.
I actually do have something
to trouble you with, Lu.
For Miss Xin's body
to fully recover,
it will take some time.
While you wait,
could you help me translate some
ancient books?
This is...
A War Demon book.
What?
Are War Demon books not books?
For the inheritance of civilization,
the books and language of the War Demons
are also a part of civilization
and should be passed down.
How are you so sure
that I'd know
the language of the War Demons?
War Demons have vigorous blood and qi.
Their pulse is large but gentle
and calm.
All 3 parts of their wrists are large.
They are innately 100 times stronger than normal people.
Anyone with some medical knowledge
can easily discover
your identity, Lu.
Since you knew,
why did you still save me?
I feel a connection with you.
I want to be your friend.
Even if I am a War Demon?
Even if you are a War Demon.
Meeting you today
feels like catching up with an old friend.
Lu,
whether you agree or not,
I want to be your friend.
Okay.
I agree.
Thank you.
I saw Tai Shiqian and the others.
The Qinghong Sect collected their remains
and built tombs and steles for them
right behind the paper mill.
When you wake up,
I'll take you
to burn incense for them.
I found that the Qinghong Sect
has some surviving
woodblocks of Unparalleled Secret Magic.
Fu Tian said
he will go to the warehouse tomorrow
to help me look for them.
If Lord of Rust-Sword knew,
he'd have been happy.
Xin Mei,
wake up soon.
Want some wine?
Care for a drink?
When did you get here?
Lu Qianqiao,
why do you like her so much?
If you came to me
just to talk about such
boring nonsense,
then you should find someone else.
I was just kidding.
Are you really mad?
In a Qinghong Sect this big,
is there no one else you can chat with?
There used to be.
But
they were killed by the immortal sects of the Central Plains.
I'm sorry.
It's nothing.
I have many enemies;
there's always hatred going back and forth.
It's good to have someone
dig up old scores for me.
What are your plans next?
When Xin Mei wakes up,
I'll take her away from here.
Where to?
Back to the Central Plains.
Homesick?
I don't have a home.
What a coincidence.
I don't have a home either.
Our backgrounds match so well,
we really are a match made in heaven.
Lu Qianqiao,
do you still remember
what your home looked like?
I remember.
In my home,
there was a big, round moon,
just like this one.
Isn't the moon like this
everywhere?
It's different.
The moon at home was exceptionally bright.
Even without lighting a candle,
you could see the whole village clearly.
I remember
lying on the grass.
The wind blowing through my fingertips
was sweet and fragrant.
The flowers at home were red.
They blossomed vibrantly,
covering the entire hillside.
When I looked up at the sky,
I only saw waves rolling on the horizon,
endlessly green.
Lu Qianqiao,
do you know where that is?
That's your hometown.
How would I know?
That's true.
Even I have forgotten.
How could anyone else know?
I almost forgot the real business.
Let's go.
I'll take you to see a good show.
My good brother.
Brother.
We shall roam the martial world together.
I'll listen to you, Brother.
Master, he is here.
Have a seat.
Nice!
The play just started.
You're right on time.
Do you also like watching plays, Lu?
I haven't watched many.
Why?
Plays are all about other people's stories.
I don't like listening to them.
If that's what you think,
you're mistaken.
Although plays
are about others,
if you really listen to them,
you will find
the lyrics expressive
and the melody touching.
Every frown, every smile,
every action and movement
seems to reflect your own heart.
When the play ends and the crowd disperses,
you only feel a sense of sorrow.
You cannot tell
if the play is about yourself,
or if you are already in the play.
Please.
It's so lively.
What are they singing about?
This play
is about 2 friends
who grew up together.
They agreed to explore the martial world together.
Later, they got separated.
One went south,
and the other went north.
Ten years later,
they met again.
One became a high official,
but the other
became a bandit.
It really is
a sorrowful story.
Not only that.
The child who became a bandit
lost his memory
and forgot everything.
He forgot everything?
Why?
Perhaps along the way,
he experienced too many hardships,
couldn't bear it,
and simply didn't want to remember.
Listening closely, I feel so angry.
These chattering people are all scoundrels.
Since ancient times, officials and bandits have their fates intertwined.
Kill the soldiers, sever the ties.
It happens today.
It's these
friends-to-enemies plots again.
So boring.
Nice!
Brother.
Brother...
He remembered.
Unfortunately, it's too late.
When a person dies, it's the end.
They can never come back.
There's a turning point.
They went back to the past.
This time, the child who became a bandit
followed the official all the way north.
They fought side by side
and looked out for each other.
They defeated strong enemies together
and destroyed the oppressive dynasty.
Fallen flowers may bloom again,
but departed ones rarely return.
The full moon before my eyes sinks into the water,
turning out to be an empty dream without a trace.
It's all fake.
Yes.
All of this
was just the bandit's
fantasy.
His friend died
and could never come back.
Therefore,
very few people watch this to the end.
They just pretended that time reversed itself
and went back to that moment in the past,
and took that as the ending.
Lu.
If it were you,
would you rather be trapped in a dream,
or return to the present
and live a lonely life?
In this world,
there is no artifact to reverse time,
nor is there a second chance.
Once a decision is made,
you should press forward without hesitation
and forge ahead.
Right?
When I was young,
I also had a friend with whom I shared life and death.
Where is he now?
I've not seen him in a long while.
He might be long dead.
Or perhaps,
just like in this play,
he has forgotten about me.
I see.